Okay, so you've successfully downloaded
Git. Now it's time to install something
that'll make Git a little easier. So by
default, you can interact exclusively
with Git through the terminal interface
that we were using in the last video.
Um, but for beginners, that can be
somewhat difficult. So what we're going
to do is we're going to install a visual
client. Um, something that you can click
buttons and it will do everything that
you need get to do. Um, and it's helpful
to get started. Once you've used it for
a while, you may want to transition to
using the command line. Um, but let's
download that client. So, here on the
download for Windows, you'll click
download a guey and then you'll click
GitHub desktop.
Um, this is a free tool to interact with
Git and it also connects with GitHub.
So, what you're going to want to do is
you're going to want to click download
now. And then it's going to detect what
operating system you're on. And I am on
a Windows. So, you're going to want to
get the correct version. Um, I'm going
to click download. When I do, it starts
downloading it. I have, just like in the
last video, previously downloaded this.
So, I'm going to click um this installer
and open it up.
And in a second here, um, it'll launch a
window that tells me that GitHub Desktop
is being installed. It'll launch once
it's done. So, it's going to install for
a little bit and then your window is
probably going to look slightly
different from mine when it does finally
install. That is because I had to
uninstall GitHub Desktop in order to
demonstrate installing it. Um, but what
you're going to want to do is you may
have a signin button um right here on
the home screen. But if not, you're
going to come up here to file, gonna
come to options, and then you're going
to sign into your github.com account.
What what I wanted to show you is if you
click on get, you can see that the git
config commands that we ran in the last
video are stored. So that the default
branch is always named main and we've
got our email and our username here. Um
here you'll want to sign into github.com
and we will talk about that in the next
video. But if you see the app launched
then you are good to